we have month one retention that's
better than chat gpt's month one
retention Anton Osa he is the co-founder
of lovable. Dev fastest growing company
in Europe what a title growth starts
ramping up after we launch growing 1
million AR per week at some point and
that just keeps accelerating the most
important thing is talent and culture
and there's more raw available talent in
Europe when a competitor has a lot of
money do you have to raise too ready to
go
[Music]
Anton fastest growing company in Europe
what a title but first thank you so much
for joining me today man thank you Harry
it's it's always fun to talk to you that
is very very kind of you it's the
British accent but I want to start
actually pre- lovable and I spoke to a
couple of your investors in your first
company depict and so I just want to
start there what are your big takeaways
from depict that shaped how you think
about lovable we scaled super super fast
at depict as well and and we like moving
just very fast Scrappy we did that we
nailed that really well I think we did
really well on this high potential
Talent as well quite Junior with high
potential Talent you can see that from
all the uh companies coming out from the
picted the the pict Mafia is is
absolutely real um but what I think we
what works in the beginning is to say
yes onto a lot of opportunities and try
out what works once you be become more
people and you have to follow up and
maintain everything that you start you
you have to be much more focused so we
said yes to too many things at at the
pick and uh we didn't like take this one
thing that we could do 10 times better
than anyone else uh and then at as the
economics uh macro wise turned worse we
we didn't continue the scaling
trajectory that we were on initially I
was just reading an article actually
with Paul book heite the founder of
Gmail and he said you need three great
features in a product and it's really
that simple and make them really really
great do you agree with that product
Simplicity towards feature depth yeah I
I think just on a produ product level
you should say no to as many things as
possible and make it more of like an
apple feeling the things you do you do
them the purpose okay and so we have hey
don't say uh yes to everything is there
anything else which you did or didn't do
that really shaped how you think about
the early days of lovable no I think
moving fast um and I I would say Talent
is the most important thing and culture
how you work together every day like how
people interact and collaborate quickly
uh those are the two most important
thing for for almost any company okay
let's just unpack talent because it's
been a I spoke to Frederick at creandum
before this and he said we had to chat
about this too you favor Talent overe
experience which sounds kind of obvious
respectfully you're going to go for like
an like an experienced untalented
person but how how do you think about
your hiring lessons around experience
versus Talent um so I think experience
can be a negative thing in some cases
you often want people who are super
ambitious they have a lot to prove and
they are more open-minded towards how
how you should work together in a team H
so um I mean for many RS I I think uh
junior Talent is is first of all super
easy to to get them into the company
they don't they're not uh already
committed to some like many their
projects the best people that you can
hire at a young age they would go on and
become Founders and then you can't hire
them anymore right so so that's why
junior uh people are often quite good
will you hire them if they haven't done
what you're hiring them to do before the
benefits often of hiring someone
experiences well I can see they've been
at X company for four years they can do
that at my company will you hire someone
who hasn't done what you asking them to
do before in most cases yes uh but I
mean if it's engineering you have to
know software engineering of course um
and you for some roles you definitely
want in that domain someone with a lot
of experience like that who can coach
and who can uh tell the more Junior
people what Great Looks Like These are
going to sound like strange questions
but you mentioned the word ambition
there did you always know that you would
be successful when you were younger
building did you always think I will be
successful in something that I do I no I
don't think so I I I I was always
frustrated with how people around me
didn't understand things as quickly as
me it felt like and then after at some
point I felt like well sometimes it's me
um being too naive I like that's
something I learned over time but uh
many of the like truths about what's
going to happen in the future have I
have a very good track track record on
and I think that's my this one of the
superpowers that have made me have made
me successful so I I felt I had that
superpower I didn't know it would
translate into building something
successfully how did you first make
money what was your first
entrepreneurial thing Anton ooh I think
so I always uh nerded out with kind of
computers and setting up our um like
land parties when I was a kid and so on
and so I noticed that all neighbors and
like friends or families they had the
comp computers and they had some issue
and then they called they wanted my help
and many of them wanted to pay me
afterwards so that became a bit of a
side hustle when I was I was a young
teenager did you do gaming when you were
younger yeah
yeah you're like the I'm so sorry to be
rude but you're like the easiest like
archetype because you fit like all the
characteristics of like successful
Founders that I have on the show it's
like number one made money early number
two exceling gaming uh both very very
clear um archetypes I want to move to
lovable so GPT engineer starts as a side
project where does the idea come from
we've left to pick G uh gbt engineer
starts as a side project where does the
idea come from um this was the spring
after chat GPT came out and I've been
playing with the the precursors of that
as well and I from already like a year
before then I felt there's an there's a
massive wave coming from scaling up
these models with more data and the p is
not set up for for currently not set up
for leveraging that after like I was
actually traveling with my now wife as
her engagement trip and when you're
traveling I get extra creative and there
um I don't think there was anyone who
was talking about like AI agents at the
time but I uh during those like sitting
on an airplane I was I started writing a
lot of like okay you can you should
hook them up and make uh you basically
put the large language model in a for
Loop and then you can have it to do a
lot of agentic things and then uh when
I'm back in Sweden I'm like okay where
do I apply this obviously on software
engineering and I'd been talking to
people about this and I felt no one was
really sufficiently imaginative to what
I was thinking about and I had to like
prove a point in that this is already
now with the current first versions of
chbt apis you can build an agent that
writes code and then I put together that
there were two I drank a lot of coffee
and then I just crammed away and um I
got the first version that really
impressed people you write create a
snake game and then you get a running
snake game on your computer yeah so that
that was the the first version of what
what we're building now how long did it
take you to build V1 with that
caffeinated session I think it was um
like one main weekend and then a bit of
Polish over with a few hours here and
there on two two weekends after that
what are the biggest lessons or advice
from building many different v1s for
many Founders that are listening it
depends what you're building for
um for most like firsttime Founders I
would really focus on the user and the
user problem and say like how can I get
one person to love what I'm building in
in this V1 uh that that's my general
advice I didn't do that I just put out a
video on Twitter and it got dozens of
academic references and millions of
people using it so take me to that so we
have this weekend we released the
product what happens then dude yeah so
it wasn't clear to me that I would build
a business on this at all I thought it
was fun that there was like and this was
an open source project so I I started
nourishing like a community that went on
to work on this open source project
while I I talk went to my co-founder and
said like Okay so this thing is
absolutely huge um I've been thinking of
doing something else to be honest and
they here is like pretty like this is a
bit of a wake up call for me that it's
it might be time to find a good
replacement for me as a CTO at at picked
that's what happened next and then then
a few months passed and so a few months
pass the community continues to grow
what happens then no but I I I figure
out a good replacement for me I decide I
need I want to have a great co-founder
that I can have as like my partnering
crime here and and there was a guy who
is the most super efficient zero fluff
and and engineer and
entrepreneur so he had sold a company
previously that I wanted to work with
and I I I biked to apartment and said
hey let's take a walk and uh plan the
future so he I got him him on board and
then we started building and created the
first version of what became loveable
lovable okay so we're building the first
version of lovable you've got your
co-founder talk to me about that time
when did we release and how did the
official release go with lovable as a
product in company so the the launch of
lovable like the product was one year
after we started building and um in the
meantime time we launched like great
listed preview versions called GPT
engineer app that was I mean that that's
the getting user feedback cycle and um
building building up I guess some some
excitement about what we were work
working on and employer branding as well
and the the first versions I I think
they were very good as they were good
they were not very good and we had some
people really liking it but the like the
Thea moments didn't click for
sufficiently many people like okay this
is how I get real value from this when
we when we went on to iterate over the
coming year we packaged together all of
these things so that you can ask today
lovable I want to build the basically a
SAS business and then people have built
their entire SAS companies and get made
made money by just prompting our AI I
just want I just want to break down a
couple of different things that you said
there you mentioned the weight list do
you have any big lessons or advice on
how to do a weight list strategy well I
think the weight lists are useful in
that you can control exactly how many
people you want to get on board and take
user interview interviews with with so I
think that's the like just get
sufficiently many people on the weight
list find a good way to qualify who you
want to talk to like you have you
probably have a different hypothesis on
who should get who you should talk to
who you're going to sell into who you're
who has the most value from your product
and then uh qualify only those and talk
to them when you do the user interviews
and user feedback sessions what are your
big lessons or piece of advice on how to
do them well what questions are good
what questions are bad any lessons uh so
there there I think for us there are two
different type of user to use we we had
this this type where we just see them
use the product and see like where do
they do they understand the product and
so that's more of a you user experience
interiew um and the other one is uh to
understand like if they have just tried
the product a bit we ask them okay so
you tried the product a bit what's why
are you even interested in this and ask
them like what problems they're facing
in their business try to identify what's
the biggest pain point that you that
they're actually looking to solve it
might be oh I want to get more customers
and I think I can get more customers if
I can show to my customers that I can
get the first version out with AI more
more quickly H so those those type of
questions how does it change the
structure of teams when you look at
teams today you have obviously software
Engineers you have designers you have
developers you have front end you have
backend how does it change the structure
of teams themselves Harry if you want to
create a personal website for you it's
super productive you can do it you don't
have a team it's just you you just
create it with AI if you want to ship
the first version of yourselves and
start making money it's all you it's not
a team like a team just slows you down
maybe you get some input from a designer
like he how does this how do you think
it's just look and and so on uh but once
you have existing
software with users and then you want to
iterate and change that software
AI
might absolutely bring
down kind of mess up your entire
codebase I might mess up your code base
so then you would want to work with a
software engineer that knows how to
bring have quality and consistently keep
quality in the product you mentioned
like people took a bit of time to find
that aha moment how important is the
time to aha moment I think it's very
important and it's funny because you
asked me this question and I I think we
are very bad at making the time to a
moment super short I think we could like
double our conversion rates if we become
better at uh like speed to a h moment
but you I can say something we're doing
let me take credit for something when
you come to love
you just see a prompt box it's very
inviting instead of getting to a landing
page you you see a prompt box and then
for the ones that do enter a prompt box
you get a quite a quick a of the first
aham and there has to be many aha
moments in lovable it's quite a complex
a software engineer is a very complex
feature but uh that that we are doing
well and that's what I I would recommend
just give the user something interactive
with instant reward you mentioned that
the prompt box itself I've had many
guests on the show say before that
almost the biggest sin that chat GPT did
was make chat the default UI for a
future of AI do you think that bluntly
chat and the prompting that we have
today in in lovable and many other
products is the right default UI for an
age of AI I think yes prompting can you
can do almost anything with prompting
and explaining your thoughts in in
written form it's um er it's also easy
to implement an itate on but but it's
going to get more advanced over time
with not just prompting I love the way
you took a deep breath there it's like
this is a weighty
question I'm thinking about it a lot I
mean you're building the interface for
creating software and no one knows what
that interface is going to look like but
the prompt thing yes I think it remains
but I'm kind of going chronologically
through the story because it's an
amazing story um you rejected YC at some
point yeah talk to me why did you reject
YC we felt that at uh best YC would be a
lot of dilution and some acceleration
but a lot of dilution and some
acceleration and at worst it would be a
distraction H to go to SF and go through
all of these like fun things that happen
when you go to YC um and we we just took
some funding instead and uh built focus
on Talent the seed round when does the
seed round come does that come post
launch or pre-launch so that comes
before we launch the first the first
waight list of our product even okay how
did that seed round go so before you've
launched the weight list of the product
how did that round go how did it come to
be yeah so I I I have this advice that
I've always gone by which is to work
with investors that you like and I I had
some people that I know from before that
I just think are amazing people that I
want to have by my side and if things go
sour if things go well uh and I spoke to
a few uh I kept it very very brief I got
like a preemptive offer and I said yeah
let's let's do it I love it how big was
this round so we took three million and
then we added on um I got the advice to
say like yeah just to get a lot of cash
because you never know what happens in
the markets so we we raised a quite a
large pre uh with an up to uh almost $8
million would you advise Founders to
raise quite large preed rounds if they
can if the money is on the table would
you say take it depends on how you want
to operate like if you like talking to
investors which at the time I was like
no I just want to build the technology
then then the answer sure take ra a big
pred so you can you get time to figure
things out um if
you like talking to investors which I um
I think you should
if you think it's an interesting to just
talk to a lot of interesting people who
care about understanding the market then
I would go more race more iteratively
smaller smaller runs we're seeing a lot
of Founders today be immensely dilution
sensitive from day one in a way that
they haven't been before like 10% is
like the max they're willing to give up
on a round how did you think about
dilution sensitivity uh here again like
I have a very wise person who was like
no dilution does does matter so much
it's all about the size of the pie and
I I think that was I was both affected
by that advice as so as my like no
minimized ution this is this is my life
life's work so that's mainly how I think
about it now so we now raise this round
we have the wait list we're skipping a
little bit take me to go live day when
when does that happen and how does go
live go we go live with lavall the 21st
of November last year 21st of November
last year that was only four months
ago yes four months ago isn't it nuts
how much like life changes in four
months it's true it can change really
fast yes yeah so November
2024 you launch from day one is it just
nuts How does it go um so I mean we had
users paying users on like earli version
that was called something else um and
then our launch
I think it wasn't one of these like wow
launches I I think we could have gotten
like 10 times more press on the launch
100% um but people start noticing like w
this is really good and and we continue
to quickly improve things in the
products chip things very rapidly um so
it ramps like growth starts ramping up
after we launch and we we like wow we're
growing 1 million AR per week at some
point and and that just keeps going
accelerating through that was in
December and that it just keeps ACC
accelerating
we it was a bit on the technical side it
was a bit frustrating because we have we
have some a lot of scaling issues that
we run into and the team is like okay we
can continue to uh patch this but they
say like we let's rewrite everything
while we're seeing this explosive growth
and there's so
many quick fixes that we want to do on
the product side so you roted ASAP and
stabilized it then yeah so it took a bit
more than eight weeks I mean it's not
completely done to date but that we took
eight weeks and then now we're shipping
faster can I ask you you mentioned that
like a millionaire r a week how much are
you growing now a week two million year
per week two million a week now
yeah like
it's so funny for me dude CU like when
you live in a world Adventure you don't
you don't kind of get this I don't think
and I don't mean that rudely to you but
like your companies go from like one to
four in a year and that's like a
four a in a year amazing that would be
good and then you're like growing 2
million a in a week does that sink in
like do you know how nuts that is no I
guess no I I mean um I a lot of things
last few weeks have just blunted me and
I'm just I'm just focused on all the
things that we have to fix and like
improve and that's all I think about
what do you think are the most common
ways or methods that company's
development process slows down for
Founders listening what should they
watch out for that often happens what
makes product development slower is
usually that you have a complex product
and you have a lot of requirements on
your product so you you said earlier har
that you have three three things that
are good in your product I think that's
uh generally A very wise thing to do
Simplicity leads to product Direction
knowing where you're going and what
you're working on when you look back
since the start of lovable where from a
product perspective did you invest and
spend time where was the benefit of
hindsight you shouldn't have done I
think at Lev ball we we thought a lot
about the community and like Community
features inside of the product and the
that I think that could have made a lot
of sense if we had seen slower growth
but now that you just like growth is not
something we not a concern you don't
need Community features to power growth
so that I think that was pretty much
waste waste of effort do you agree with
the sentiment build it and they will
come the growth has been amazing from
day one it feels like since gbt engineer
even people have just kind of come for
the product because it's been amazing
and different do you believe and they
will come actually does stand true today
if you have a very strong vision of
how that where there is untapped
potential if you really know that deep
down and you have track record of
showing that then build it and they will
come is going to work um uh and and you
also have the runway your personal like
energy Runway and so on to really make
it work and they make them come but for
in most most cases yeah that is too
risky it's too risky to just build it
and they will come and it's you can
build it and make them come or try to
make them come at the same time and
that's much lower lower risk you said
there about energy and it reminded me of
a statement that Nick revolute said to
me in a show when he was talking about
his investing and he said the most
successful Founders that he invests in
are between 30 and 35 they don't have
the naivity of the incredibly young
founders but they don't have the bluntly
tiredness in some ways or that you know
you have more energy when you're younger
of older Founders how do you think about
that given your age today I think energy
is uh super important and uh I think the
navity is is a benefit often but uh I
mean I I I made mistake a lot of
mistakes was the first time manager as
well that uh dep picked pretty much what
was the biggest mistake he made thinking
that we should change the culture and
become a more of a scale up something
slow moving or like more management
layers when we became 40 people that's
that was the biggest mistake I did why
did you think
that that was I mean my
co-founder
um and other senior people we spoke to
said like oh now you have to hire
Executives and so on and that uh was um
that was a bad idea that okay and so did
you start hiring Executives pretty much
yeah or yeah we did and then they don't
work uh one person I hired didn't work
out uh which slowed me down and they
kind of set us back a lot and so when
you think about that what would your
advice be to other Founders don't
believe the you can scale way
longer without exag many Founders hire
more mercenary style maybe like skilled
people but just like they are running in
their Lane
um I hire generalists and I like try to
empower them as much as possible and if
you have a lot of General super super
smart generalist that you're um doing a
lot of smart like new initiatives and so
on adding Executives on top of them um
is high risk and like reward is
questionable it's at some point of
course it makes sense does culture break
at any point when you're scaling user
base so fast you're scaling Revenue so
fast I mean usually I think it does yes
or it changes it changes it evolves um
for this is something I'm very mindful
about and I why I'm so scared of adding
too many heads what are you worried
about the most important thing for
everyone at our company I which I talk
about is uh to role model how much you
care about the product the users the
entire the team how how well the team
works and role model and Mak sure other
people care it as much as you and feel
that that comes from a feeling of of
ownership of the culture and the team if
you're a lot of people that gets diluted
typically
so um yeah that that's that's what
breaks or that's what's harder okay so
we have the team scaling we have user
base we have Revenue
scaling we're making actually a lot of
money at this point why a series a I
just had some scheduled checkins with
investors and there was this one guy and
his team that had like obsessed about
lavable for the last few months and they
they're hearing fedck he's here in
Stockholm at kandum and uh he G he just
gives gives an amazing impression on me
and I'm like okay I could I can wait
because I know it's very clear to me
that this is just the beginning and I
can I can could raise it later but we
can accelerate by adding an investor
that is a partner in on in helping to
find more amazing people in um just as a
sounding board Fredick helped grow
Spotify from from nothing um and uh I we
decided to raise a small round okay so
you decided to raise a small run I have
to ask this you have many well-funded
competitors in the US I think it was
Neil Murray that said you put like we're
Devon that actually works from like very
early on yeah which I thought was bold
um when a competitor has a lot of money
do you have to raise too I don't think
so no I mean you can just we could
bootstrap like you don't you can
bootstrap most things so you never have
to raise but they can outs spend you on
Talent on customers on marketing no yeah
I mean if you're
I I'm not afraid of any of those if
being out spend on any of those I think
it's the only thing that matters is
execution so if you can outperform your
own execution then I'm scared where
could you improve your execution today
we spoke about speed of shipping amazing
culture's great the talent's phenomenal
where would you say execution wise you
could
improve I think you can always improve
on like how the decision Loop on how
fast you take decisions and communicate
those decisions so that everyone is
really on the same page that's uh how
how you do that how do you make them
today how could it be improved I think
it's about doing fewer I think we could
do fewer things as well at lovable like
there's a lot of uh people with great
ideas that each each idea in isation is
great but you can only have so many you
should only execute on so many at the
same time we mentioned the team and the
culture one and we mentioned there
you've been pretty Ardent around
building in Europe keeping the team in
Europe being a European company a lot of
people say to me by staying in Europe
you are deliberately not doing what is
best for your career if you were in the
valley you would be more successful what
is your response to them the most
important thing is talent and culture
and it's more raw there's more raw
available talent in Europe uh the
culture isn't on the like the US has
more culture that fits succeeding as a
startup I have to say per default so
what what specifically do you think it
is about that culture so it's about then
theault of thinking big and being super
ambitious and being very committed to
making things work that that in Europe
people are more like about uh living a
balanced uh life and uh we're we're kind
of taught that we
should um in in Sweden we we talk
about the law of jante which is that you
should be better than others okay yes
this so This concerns me so how do you
respond to people who say you would be
more successful if you were in the
valley we would be S so if you're a
Founder I think you you
have more free entropy of like talents
to use and channel into some into
something successful but there are of
course many benefits from being in the
valley I think it's a bit of playing on
the on hard mode here from Europe and I
get excited about playing on hard mode
and showing that you can create a
category defining company uh which is
lovable in our case from Europe are you
positive about Europe moving forwards we
are in a doom loop around Europe which
we both disagree with and hate are you
positive and what guides your thinking
yeah I'm uh I'm super positive I think
there is a like an strong Underdog
mentality among all of us Founders now
which is usually a a winning concept to
be to feel like the underdog and having
wanting to prove others wrong I also
think there's incredible superpowers in
using the Arbitrage pricing of
incredible engineers in Europe and
selling into the US you can build huge
companies selling into the US from
Europe doesn't mean you can't sell into
the US just because you're a European
company true no it's a very Global
Market dude um I've got some questions
which are a little bit spicier but I
have to ask them okay so a spicier one
is if one were to criticize lovable they
would say amazing God look at the
revenue growth look at the user growth
but is this like AI um Sugar Sugar
Revenue in other words it's not
sustainable and it will churn very
quickly how do you respond to it's not
really real stainable revenue and it's
not sticky we have month one retention
that's better than chat gpt's month one
retention on paying customers and so
it's about
85% and that um that is just going up
like they of course there's a lot of
things to be desired when you working
with an AI system there's a fraction of
people some people that come in and
they're they just like flip up their
credit card because they want to try
they they want to learn which is
rational thing to do and then they know
that they are going to stop using it
almost they almost know so we have a
fraction of users who are like those
people wow 85% month one yeah wow that's
great because you're also too early to
have month six what could you do today
to increase retention most significantly
the easiest thing we can do is to
give more more of the important aha
moments to ensure that every all of our
users get more of the important aha
moments on how to use the product I I I
don't I don't really respectfully agree
or get you because like you give prompts
Under The Prompt box so you say like
build me a sass app or build me a dog
website or whatever the prompt is dude
all you need to do is click it and you
see the code being written and then you
see it being created like the aha moment
is pretty obvious no so there are many
aha moments for or like education
moments to get the most value get the
full value out of using it and there the
most important of those are with regards
to when the when you feel like you're
getting stuck and the AI doesn't
understand you and there's a there are
many things in how to get around around
that that you can pick up as user it is
how you about how you prompt it's about
how to understand what doesn't work and
explain or explain clearly what what the
what the problems you're seeing what
what you find could be the problem when
you're building a more complex feature
and it's about that you can actually
onboard an engineer to do small changes
to the code base like those are things
our users should know and not everyone
knows them what's your norstar matric
today if you have one metric on the TV
for the whole team to focus on what is
it um it's the number of uh users that
go all the way to getting like users on
what they built getting getting
something hosted with users on what they
built that's what we focus on what's the
amount today so we have almost 40,000
paying users and then that's the proxy
for that wow 40,000 PES as okay do
you care about the time it takes to go
from start to website created or not we
care about I I have to say Harry like
the these things about the onboarding
and how much can improve um is not
something that I we have had focus on
like we were just making the core AI
Parts better better better that's what
we focus on okay so you say about making
the core AI Parts better better better
yeah amazing people also say ah rappers
on top of other people's models why are
they wrong with that assumption I mean
it's very easy to create a cool demo
with just a rapper it's super easy to
make a cool demo with just a rapper the
hard part is to get to or get close to
100% you get what you're asking for and
there's a lot of small
details in making that work there's a
lot of small details and there's a chain
of at large language model API calls and
other algorithms that run and that chain
is like you can continue to optimize
that for years without reaching
Perfection whose models do you sit on
top of today we we use all of open AI
models Google Gemini and the main
Workhorse is anthropics Claud model for
writing the code I was going to have
this in a quick F but I have to ask it
now you've got anthropic at 60 billion
you've got open AI at 300 or you've got
grock at 50 which do you buy and which
do you sell okay so um I
think I would I I care about the best
talent here and I feel like uh Elon is
very good at tent so I would buy I would
buy Gro I think they're also very
ruthless in like finding business
opportunities we we'll see about that
but I feel like they could be good at
that even though anthropic is my
favorite I love the the culture and I
love the like the leadership there um
and I will short open AI because they're
they're like have been very good in the
scrappy face but they they haven't
proven that they can um we have a clear
product Direction and focus now over the
last years
so I would push sorry I'm it's a Sunday
we're allowed to be a little bit more
casual I would push back on you and go
the two biggest things that matter in
this next wave is brand yeah recognition
on the consumer side and it's consumer
facing frontend products and when you
look at Brand everyone's mother knows
chat GPT they don't even know open AI
but they know chat GPT and then on the
consumer product side respectfully
they're way ahead of anyone
else that's true am I wrong I just I
just think we're still early in the days
of AI and if you look at the Enterprise
Revenue like anthropic is almost caught
up to open AI from nothing from being
absolutely dominated and I don't know
what Gro is going to do here but I
expect them to be having a like open a I
lost all their best talent to to
anthropic I think Gro might be able to
pull something off here I spoke to a
very wise friend of mine before this and
they said that the biggest conc that I
have is that open source or Mega corpse
of the world with massive distribution
advantages come in and win the market
how do you think about that and is that
a concern the big Mega Corps they move
very slowly in many domains so they're
never going to in many years they're not
going to have the best product on the
market there are distribution advantages
for some of this Mega Corps and that's
like the marketing and distribution is
is what I'm more concerned about um but
overall it's going to be like a growing
Market where you can easily as a startup
be both best position for some parts of
the market one thing that's going to be
a real shift I imagine that you have to
face is the shift from plg and kind of
prosumer to Enterprise how do you think
about that shift and is that just not a
concern given the speed of Revenue ramp
how do you think about that um yeah I
think if we would do Enterprise I would
want to do that really well so we're
holding off with doing Enterprise for
now we're holding off and U our goal you
may asked about the north Zone north
star metric what we want to have is we
want to be the best place for for
Builders to create products and get the
hund get get a million of the most
talented builders on lovable and if we
succeed in that that's a great segue
into many other areas including
Enterprise when you look at
Shopify what do you learn from them
blazing a trial in the way they have
done as efficiently as they have done i'
I'd I'd love to hear from you har what's
the what do what are you most impressed
by with Shopify honestly I would say
it's their narrative around everyone
being an entrepreneur I think Harley's a
phenomenal communicator and Storyteller
at bringing very real businesses to life
and how Shopify changed their processes
their sales and really made an impact
and I I love to and I think he's
obviously a brilliant technologist but I
think without Harley's storytelling
narrative entrepreneurial Vibes to life
it would be a different company so I
would learn from that a lot in terms of
how to tell your customers
stories yeah to not totally I I think
Shopify um has been able to execute on
many things and just created a good
package I they've iterated fast that's
my impression they've iterated fast on
serving all the needs for for building
your e-commerce and I think this
velocity is was one the most important
thing for building the best product when
we look forward dude what would you most
like to build in the product but for
whatever reason you cannot why what
would that reason be I think I can build
anything into the product really like
team would block you um that PRI
prioritization not the right time okay
so something that we have to say no to
right now yeah so I'd love to build in a
way for Founders to get everything you
get out the Y combinator into lavable so
that that includes like some marketing
infrastructure why comor has that uh all
the entire Playbook and going above that
and even saying like oh here's your
Incorporated Delaware C comp company
your stripe setup you just have to focus
on the product and talking to users and
creating content for marketing when you
look at partnership ships today apis
that we have today into the different
providers that's that's quite a real and
possible product yes yes it's a it's on
the road map wow yeah good okay well YC
are going to love you after this show
uh um final one when we look forward
dude what concerns you most if you had
to choose was it be regulatory
challenges competition or hype Cycles I
think if someone competitors is super
super good at marketing uh that would
concern me how important is
brand I think brand is mainly the
outcome of your product there's other
factors too and then so I mean product
is the important thing and then product
good product plus awareness just creates
brand that's that's I think was
sufficient so it's more of a downstream
effect of something else then it is
important when you're doing 2 million a
week in in additional ARA you're going
to have more and more investors want to
give you
money how do you think about that and
what what makes it worth it to take
versus this is a distraction get out of
my face it's currently it's a
distraction I think it might make it
worth it it will make it worth it when
we know know how to exactly how we want
to spend the money or it's a partner we
really want to work with and um it's
like terms where we we would never
regret saying yes to them what if done
would be a massive needle mover for the
company one or two more of the perfect
technical product
hires dude I could talk to you all day I
want to move into a quick fire around so
I say a short statement you give me your
thought so yeah what do you believe that
most around you disbelieve I think we
have models today that are really smart
I think that's where people don't agree
with me they're they're smarter than
humans but they don't have memory in the
same extent as we do they don't have
context how fast will we ramp context in
memory given scaling today it's the ramp
what you need to ramp is to decide what
like the the process for storing memory
I think is what you have to ramp and it
has to store all of these things like my
conversation with Harry has to be stored
somehow into the system and all like my
childhood almost has to be stored as
well I don't know it's going to take
years you can buy and hold one public
stock for the next 10 years which one do
you buy and hold um some Talent play
would and what comes to mind is Tesla
and they're also interestingly
positioned outside of uh software wow
okay what was the most important trait
in a Founder that no one talks about U
okay I think great judgment people
probably talk about but but I think um I
like people who hire like see potential
in people it's like okay this this
person can become amazing and and the
Judgment in picking Talent like that
what's your biggest weakness as CEO
today um I'm not as good as multitasking
as I would like to
be if lovable failed tomorrow what would
be the reason like investors WR a
premortem which is like a reason why
something doesn't work what is that um
we lose momentum and excitement and
that's like that's what fuels us today
right all the excitement and the
momentum what have you changed your mind
on in the last 12 months you don't need
to be attached to One Foundation model
provider they're all going to be amazing
you don't need to there's not going to
be one winner here are we seeing
Foundation models be completely
commoditized
yes we won't see specializations like we
do today I know Claude is better for
codee and
Engineering do you think that will
really uh equalize yeah I love the sweds
one word
answers um what's your favorite failure
um I I think so when I was 17 I failed
my exams at school Anton I failed them
badly yeah like D D's across the board
and I I looked at myself and I was like
I'm either going to work behind a bar or
I can make something of my life mhm and
I chose to work harder than ever and
make something of my life
um that is my favorite failure I think
my favorite
failure um I
probably that I didn't
um the pict didn't work out so I could
do more things what concerns you most in
the world today I think that leadership
in this in the world today I I love that
whole leadership to be true idealists
and not like function of circumstances
and the people to pleas um and be much
more open-minded to people who disagree
with them and super intelligent as well
but leadership in the world today uh are
usually like a bit corrupted and uh
narrow-minded and that's what concerns
me do you think they would say you're
naive I uh like I want to be naive to to
the challenges of leadership to the
challenges of having a you know a voter
population you sometimes have to be
certain ways I think we used to have
like better presidents and leaderships
in throughout the last century so no I
don't think I'm too n but I'm definitely
always a bit I totally agree with you I
think the state of leadership today is
woeful um who penultimate one what's
your biggest short in the public markets
I not so read well read on the public
market it would be a SAS company it
would be like a SAS company that has a
per seat
pricing where th those their
ICP um is going to be replaced by AAS
that just replaces the employees so the
the number of SE goes down what's the
future pricing in an AI world yeah I
think it depends on how defensible your
you like your business is if you're
selling to like Enterprises that never
change SAS software you should try to
make some value based pricing I don't
know how you how you get the good value
based pricing but I would do something
like that otherwise I think you should
should don't innovate so much too much
on pricing do what do whatever works
today I love the facial expressions uh
my my final one I like optimism and I
think we need more of it in the world
I'm incredibly excited for the next
decade because I think we'll find cures
to my mother's got multiple curosis
which is a horrible disease I think
we'll find cures to diseases that we
really didn't think possible before what
excites you most about the next decade
that we have coming I think it's that AI
is hopefully going to make us humans
understand each other better and be
better at doing win-win playing win win
and that would be awesome I'm excited
about that so like you our leadership
actually being um enhanced by super
intelligent AI Anton listen dude I've so
enjoyed doing this thank you so much for
joining me and thank you for inspiring a
generation of European entrepreneurs
that they can build unbelievable
businesses is in Europe thank you har it
was it was super fun